mintvine.com 2017-06-11

# MintVine | MintVine Privacy Policy | MintVine

## MintVine Privacy Policy

Last Updated:  2/7/2017

**MINTVINE WEBSITE PRIVACY POLICY**

Branded Research, Inc. (" **BRINC** ," " **us** " or " **we** "), the operator of www.mintvine.com and its associated websites and services (collectively, the " **Site** ") values the privacy of our users, members, and others (collectively or individually " **Users** ") who visit and use the Site.  This statement governs information you provide to us or that we learn from your use of the Site and tells you how we may collect, use, and in some instances share, this information.

**The Information BRINC Collects**

User Provided Information:  You may provide to BRINC what is generally called "personally identifiable" information when you register, such as your name and e-mail address.  In addition, BRINC gives you the option to provide us with certain demographic information about yourself and to upload photographs or other personally identifiable information.  In order to become a member of the Site you are required to provide information through the registration process.  At this time, BRINC will ask for your name, email, address, telephone number, IP address, and general demographic information about yourself, including household information and personal interests.  BRINC is able to tailor its efforts to its users by receiving more (and accurate) information about them.  You may edit your account information at anytime by logging in to your account with your username and password and going to the My Account tab underneath your name in the Dashboard.  Any and all changes will be made immediately once you hit Save.  Please update this information as you see fit so that BRINC maintains accurate information about you.

"Cookies" Information:  When you visit the Site, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer.  BRINC uses both session cookies and persistent cookies.  A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Site.  By using these cookies, we can "remember" what you have done on the Site before and personalize our site for you.  These persistent types of cookies can be removed.  Each web browser implements different functionality, so please refer to the manuals or technical support resources that are available in conjunction with your web browser to learn the correct way to modify your cookies set-up.  If you are using the Site in a jurisdiction where your prior consent is required for us to deploy any particular cookies, you will be asked to accept such cookies before they are deployed.  Please note that disabling cookies or declining to accept certain cookies will prevent you from accessing some of the functionality and site offerings available via the Site. 

"Automatically Collected" Information:  When you visit the Site or open one of our HTML emails, we may record certain information from your web browser by using different types of technology, including "clear gifs" or "web beacons."  This "automatically collected" information may include your Internet Protocol address ("IP Address"), web browser type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after the Site, the pages you view on our site, and the dates and times that you visit.

"Optionally Collected" Information: By agreeing to participate and installing MintVine Go on your computer and/or mobile device, you are granting us permission to passively collect information about your online behavior. When you use your computer, we may record the identity of the websites you visit, what time you visited those websites, how long you spent browsing or using them, the words and phrases you input into search engines, which search engines you use, the software and applications you use in order to browse online and use the internet. You have the ability to pause or uninstall the MintVine Go at any time.

**The Way BRINC Uses Information  **

BRINC uses the information that we collect to provide to you all of the features and services found on the Site.  When you complete offers and surveys on the Site, BRINC will need to identify you so that we can determine you completed any offer or survey and that we can also credit your account accordingly. BRINC may also use your email address to correspond with you and notify you of offers or surveys that we deem to be a good fit. We may use your email address for marketing purposes, unless you have expressly notified us that you prefer for us not to use your email address for any specific marketing purposes ("opt-out").  While you may opt-out from such marketing use, you may not opt-out from our use of your email address for non-marketing or administrative purposes such as automatic notifications of recent account activity, or notifying you of major site updates.

BRINC may use all of the information that we collect from our Users to understand the usage trends and preferences, to improve the way the Site works and looks, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, and to create new features and functionality.

As part of this process, we may use Google Analytics to provide us with aggregated information about how Users interact with the Site, and may set cookies and/or use web beacons for this purpose. The information gathered by the Google Analytics software (including any personal information about you) will be sent to Google where it will be stored and used by Google in accordance with its own privacy policy rather than ours.  Please review the Google Privacy Policy http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ or contact Google for more information.

BRINC allows other users to view your name, other profile details and photographs should you provide this information and make it publicly viewable.

BRINC may use automatically collected information and cookies information to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Site; (b) provide custom, personalized advertisements, content and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; and (d) monitor aggregate usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.

MintVine Go will operate passively in the background and will not affect your connection speed. We will not intentionally use MintVine Go to collect highly sensitive Personal Information such as passwords, usernames, social security or personal identification numbers, financial information (other than the fact that you may have visited the website or used the app of a financial institution or similar company) or health information (other than the fact that you have visited a health insurance or healthcare provider website or performed searches related to a particular medical condition or health concern).

**When BRINC Discloses Information  **

BRINC, by nature of its business, connects you with different third parties through their offers and surveys.  In the event that you subscribe to or opt-in a third-party offer or survey, BRINC may provide your information to the third-party so that we can facilitate the relationship between you and the third party.  In many cases you will be asked directly by third parties to give them your personally identifiable information. This may happen when you complete an offer or a survey or when you use their own websites or by other means.  BRINC is not responsible for any information you provide Third Parties.  BRINC suggest reading those privacy policies associated with those third parties.

BRINC may disclose both personally identifiable and automatically collected information to affiliated companies or other businesses or persons to process such information on our behalf, to provide website maintenance and security, to offer certain features on the Site, to assist us in improving the way the Site works and looks, and to create new features.  We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy, we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information, and we require these parties to use any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

BRINC may share automatically collected and other aggregated non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties for their use and distribution for their business purposes, including without limitation for the purposes of assisting them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, and promotions.

BRINC may share optionally collected information to develop statistics about Internet use and online activity and provide in aggregate for clients regarding trends in consumer behavior and consumer interest for future and/or present products and services. 

We may share personally identifiable information with other third-party organizations for their marketing or promotional use without your consent, except with respect to any specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-out.

We may disclose your personally identifiable information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with laws or to respond to subpoenas, court orders, warrants or other legal demands or to establish or defend BRINC from legal claims; or (b) to protect and defend our rights or property, you, or third parties from fraud, abuse or violations of the Terms of Service or illegal acts; or (c) to protect the safety or integrity of BRINC, its users, the public or other parties as it is deemed appropriate, in our sole discretion. You hereby consent to our sharing your personally identifying information under the circumstances described herein.

We may also share your personal information and/or social-demographic information, including, without limitation, a unique identification number ("UID"), postal code, gender, marital status, education, ethnicity/race (where permitted by applicable law), employment related information, and non-personally identifiable information on household members, with third party sample/market research companies (individually each a "Third Party MR Company" and collectively the "Third Party MR Companies") for the purpose of identifying survey opportunities that you may be eligible for through the Third Party MR Companies. If you are eligible for a survey opportunity, the Third Party MR Company will provide your unique identification number and a survey link to us and we will invite you to participate in the survey. We will not share your name, email address, or phone number with the Third Party MR Companies. In connection with the sharing of your information with a Third Party MR Company, your information may be transferred and stored outside of your country of residence, including, without limitation, in the United States. If you have any questions about this data sharing please contact us using the details below or alternatively you can opt-out by deleting your account from your Preferences page. Your participation in such survey opportunities does not entitle you to any benefits offered by, or membership with, the Third Party MR Companies.

Except as otherwise noted in this Privacy Policy, BRINC does not share personal information about Users with third parties unless doing so is appropriate to carry out a User’s request or it reasonably believes that doing so is legally required or is in BRINC’ interest to protect its property or other legal rights or the rights or property of others.

BRINC’s accountability for personal data that it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, BRINC remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless BRINC proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**User Profile and Password**

You have access to your personal information and you may update, correct, or delete your member information and email preferences at any time.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting Users profile access.  YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE SECRECY OF YOUR UNIQUE PASSWORD AND ACCOUNT INFORMATION AT ALL TIMES. 

PLEASE NOTE THAT WITH THE EXCEPTION OF CERTAIN CATEGORIES OF INFORMATION AS IDENTIFIED BY BRINC FROM TIME TO TIME, ALL INFORMATION THAT YOU POST FOR VIEWING ON THE SITE IS MADE PUBLICLY AVAILABLE TO ALL USERS OF THE SITE. 

**Children**

Consistent with the federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we do not intend to collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13).  Any person who provides their personal information to BRINC through the Site represents that they are 13 years of age or older.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

The Site provides you with the opportunity to affirmatively opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about you.  The Site gives you the option to end our use of your information, and to cease receiving or otherwise having access to future communications or services

http://www.intimedesignsart.com/blasts/mintvine/mvemail.html

**Third-party Advertisers, Links to Other Sites, "Do Not Track" Policies**

BRINC may allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Site.  These third-party ad servers or ad networks may use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear within the Site.  They may automatically receive your IP Address when this happens.  They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize their advertising content.

If your web browser includes a "Do Not Track" signal when you visit the Site, BRINC will not respond to the "Do Not Track" signal, because BRINC doesn’t track users across the web except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in.

BRINC does not authorize the collection of personally identifiable information by, or provide personally identifiable information to, these third-party ad servers or ad networks except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in.  Also, please note that if an advertiser asks BRINC to show an advertisement to a certain audience or audience segment and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they were trying to reach.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks.  BRINC’ Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other ad servers or ad networks or their websites.

**Our Commitment to Data Security**

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk.  Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems.  We use secure server software (SSL) and firewalls to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be illegally or improperly accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software. 

If BRINC learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps.  By using the Site or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Site.  BRINC may post a notice on the Site if a security breach occurs.  If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the Site.  BRINC may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances.  Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.  To receive a free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us via email at privacy@mintvine.com.

**Special Note to International Users**

The Site is hosted in the United States. If you are a User accessing the Site from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States which does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and other regions, and by providing your personal data you consent to:

  * the use of your personal data for the uses identified above in accordance with the Privacy Policy; and
  * the transfer of your personal data to the United States as indicated above.

YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE LAWS OF THE UNITED STATES TREAT YOUR INFORMATION IN A MANNER THAT MAY BE SUBSTANTIALLY DIFFERENT FROM, AND LESS PROTECTIVE THAN, THE TREATMENT REQUIRED UNDER THE LAWS OF OTHER COUNTRIES AND JURISDICTIONS. IF YOU DO NOT WANT YOUR  INFORMATION TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, YOU SHOULD NOT SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH US, OR MAKE USE OF THE SITE. 

TO THE EXTENT ALLOWED BY THE LAW OF THE COUNTRY IN WHICH YOU ARE LOCATED, YOU EXPRESSLY WAIVE ANY RIGHT YOU MAY HAVE TO REQUIRE US TO TREAT YOUR IDENTIFYING INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAWS OF ANY COUNTRY OR JURISDICTION OTHER THAN THE UNITED STATES.  HOWEVER, THE FOREGOING WAIVER MAY NOT BE LEGALLY BINDING IN SOME COUNTRIES, SUCH AS THE MEMBER STATES OF THE EUROPEAN UNION.  TO THE EXTENT IT IS NOT LEGALLY BINDING IN THE COUNTRY IN WHICH YOU ARE LOCATED, THIS FOREGOING WAIVER DOES NOT APPY TO YOU.

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Policy**

BRINC complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (the “Privacy Shield”) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States.  BRINC also complies with the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework (“U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor”).  BRINC has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.  To learn more about the US-Swiss Safe Harbor and to view our certification page, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/swiss 

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor, we encourage you to contact us should you have a Privacy Shield-related (or general privacy-related) complaint. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield Policy should contact us by mail, telephone or email as follows:

Branded Research, Inc.

343 Fourth Ave, Suite 201. San Diego, CA 92101

888-848-2525

info@brinc.co

BRINC has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to BBB EU Privacy Shield, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the U.S. and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus.  If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited cirumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel. 

BRINC has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-Swiss Safe Harbor to an independent dispute resolution mechanism operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints for more information and to file a complaint.

In addition, the United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is the statutory body that has jurisdiction to hear any claims against BRINC regarding compliance with the Privacy Shield. There is a possibility, under certain conditions, for individuals to invoke last resort binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel to be created by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission.

**In the Event of Merger or Sale**

If BRINC should ever file for bankruptcy or have its assets sold to or merge with another entity, information BRINC receives from you through the Site is a BRINC asset and may be transferred to another party; however, in the event of such a transfer, we will require that the transferee agree to honor this Privacy Policy, as it applies to Users prior to the effective date of any such transfer, unless we are legally prohibited from doing so.

**Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy**

BRINC reserves the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time for any reason.  Each time BRINC exercises such right, you shall be required to affirmatively accept the updated Privacy Policy, and if you fail to do so, you will no longer be able to access or use the Site.

**Contacting BRINC**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at privacy@mintvine.com or write to us at:

MintVine  
343 4th Ave, Suite 201
